<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>USBCA Home on The United States Blind Chess Association</title>
    <link>https://.usblindchess.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content in USBCA Home on The United States Blind Chess Association</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://.usblindchess.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Challenger, First Quarter, 2024</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2024-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2024-03/</guid>
      <description>The Challenger Magazine of the United States Blind Chess Association December 2023&#xA;The mission of the USBCA is to promote the game of chess among the blind community. Website: http://usblindchess.org/&#xA;Disclaimer The views expressed in the Challenger do not necessarily reflect the policies or views of the USBCA or those of the editor.&#xA;President&amp;rsquo;s Message Well, another term has come and gone, and a new one is upon us. My thanks to those of you who exercised your right as USBCA members and cast your ballot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Challenger, Second Quarter, 2024</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2024-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2024-06/</guid>
      <description>The Challenger Magazine of the United States Blind Chess Association&#xA;June 2024&#xA;The mission of the USBCA is to promote the game of chess among the blind community.&#xA;Website: https://usblindchess.org&#xA;Note: The views expressed in the Challenger do not necessarily reflect the policies or views of the USBCA or those of the editor.&#xA;Editor’s Note By Rita Crawford&#xA;The mission of the USBCA is to promote chess among the blind community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LiChess Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/lichess-tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/lichess-tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Note: This tutorial assumes you are using a screen reader such as JAWS, NVDA, or VoiceOver, and that you are using a computer. Our thanks to the author: José María Saponara for writing the original tutorial.&#xA;1. Introduction This tutorial guides blind players through using LiChess, a free online chess platform. While not all LiChess features are accessible, this guide covers playing games, joining teams, analyzing games, and basic settings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chess Notation</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/chess-notation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/chess-notation/</guid>
      <description>Notation for Playing correspondence and Over-the-board Chess When playing correspondence games and keeping score, writing down moves, for live games, use the universal algebraic notation as described below. If you have any questions about how this works, feel free to Contact the tournament director using the below information.&#xA;Tournament Director Contact Information&#xD;Please write this information down somewhere other than on your computer in case you do&#xD;not have access to your computer when you need it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Challenger, Fourth Quarter, 2023</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2023-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2023-12/</guid>
      <description>The Challenger Disclaimer Editor&amp;rsquo;s Note Upcoming Events Chess Queens Hands On Chess Chat Important Notice Getting to Know President&amp;rsquo;s Note Change Is Afoot! Greece and Guatemala Player&amp;rsquo;s Spotlight Annotated game by Paul Benson Puzzles Easy Position Solution Harder Position Solution Difficult Position Solution The Challenger Magazine of the United States Blind Chess Association December 2023&#xA;The mission of the USBCA is to promote the game of chess among the blind community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Challenger, Third Quarter, 2023</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2023-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2023-09/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Table of Contents Disclaimer Important Notices Upcoming Events Notice Board Results of US Blind Open held in Elmhurst, IL July 21 to 23, 2023 Results of the Stephen Hilton Memorial chess tournament In Memoriam, Norm Doerner Editor&amp;rsquo;s Note President&amp;rsquo;s Message: The USBCA! Who Am Us, anyway! (The Firesign Theater) Player Spotlight, U.S. Blind Open Champion Alex Barrasso Champing At The Bit Part 2 Down To The Last Seconds Puzzles Mate in 2 and 3 Mate in two.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tournaments</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/tournaments/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/tournaments/</guid>
      <description>This is where you can find all of the United States Blind Chess Association current correspondence and realtime tournament listings and rules.&#xA;We are currently holding our 2023 Norm Doerner Revival Correspondence tournament,and our 2024 Divisional and Ladder Correspondence tournaments.&#xA;On This Page On This Page 2024 Correspondence Divisional Tournament Specific Rules 2024 USBCA Correspondence Ladder Tournament Rules General Rules For Correspondence Play Tournament Director Contact Information&#xD;Please write this information down somewhere other than on your computer in case you do&#xD;not have access to your computer when you need it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USBCA Board Minutes</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/minutes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/minutes/</guid>
      <description>Find United States Blind Chess Association board meeting minutes here.&#xA;Board Meeting, April 29, 2024, 7:00 PM central time Glenn Crawford called the meeting to order at 7:04 PM central time.&#xA;Present: Rita Crawford, Marilyn Bland, Glenn Crawford, Evan Reese, Al Pietrolungo. Apologies from Jim Homme.&#xA;Rita gave the Treasurer&amp;rsquo;s report. She indicated that opening a bank account in USBCA&amp;rsquo;s name is stalled until some other things are in place. Michael will withdraw the money in the existing account and deposit it into the account Rita will create for USBCA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chess Resources</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/resources/</guid>
      <description>Here are some chess resources that you might find useful from the United States Blind Chess Association.&#xA;Adaptive Chess Sets Chess Baron - Highly Recommended This companymakes adaptive chess sets. See Chess sets for people who are blind&#xA;Chess Links For People Who Are Blind Some of these resources are good general resources, but also accessible.&#xA;LiChess.org Free chess lessons from Paul Benson End games from Paul Benson International chess tournaments on Skype The Braille Chess Magazine (Produced by the Royal National Institute for the Blind in the UK, and available through NLS) Magnison Chess Accademy on Youtube Other Chess Associations In The Blindness Community British Braille Chess Association Ireland Braille Chess Association Austria Braille Chess Association (German Language) Italy Braille Chess Association (Italian Language) German Braille Chess Association International Braille Chess Association General Chess Links Chess from Wikipedia Chess from WikiBooks Encyclopedia of Chess Openings United States Chess Federation This Week in Chess University of Pittsburgh Chess FTP Site Accessible Chess Software Below is a compilation of accessible chess software that we know of.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact The USBCA</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/contact/</guid>
      <description>Contact the USBCA Contact the USBCA with any questions you may have about playing chess while blind or for membership information or to donate. see our Home page for information about how to join.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correspondence Tournament Standings</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/standings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/standings/</guid>
      <description>This is where you can find all of the United States Blind Chess Association divisional and special correspondence tournament standings for the current year. See the yearly Ladder standings page for the current ladder table.&#xA;Tournament Director Contact Information&#xD;Please write this information down somewhere other than on your computer in case you do&#xD;not have access to your computer when you need it. It is your responsibility to keep this contact&#xD;information where you can access it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Donate</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/donate/</guid>
      <description>The United States Blind Chess Association (USBCA) works to encourage and assist in the promotion and advancement of correspondence and over-the-board chess among chess enthusiasts who are blind or visually impaired.&#xA;It is the generosity of our donors that enables the USBCA to carry out our mission. Your support, at any level, enables us to: run correspondence tournaments, organize and conduct an annual over-the-board tournament, spread the word about the USBCA to individuals who are blind or visually impaired and provide tactile chess sets to new members.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/faq/</guid>
      <description>Here are some frequently asked questions about the United States Blind Chess Association (USBCA).&#xA;What is the history of the USBCA? The USBCA was founded in the late 1960s. Back then, it had correspondence tournaments where people sent moves in braille by postal mail. They began holding an over-the-board tournament annually in the 1970s.&#xA;How do I get a friendly game going with another USBCA member? You can send a message to our email list saying you are interested in playing a game, or you can contact our tournament director and ask for a suggestion of who you should play.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Member Ratings</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/ratings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/ratings/</guid>
      <description>Below are the current USBCA correspondence and Real Time rating lists. If you have any questions regarding the below information, please contact our tournament director using the below information.&#xA;Tournament Director Contact Information&#xD;Please write this information down somewhere other than on your computer in case you do&#xD;not have access to your computer when you need it. It is your responsibility to keep this contact&#xD;information where you can access it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Membership Information</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/membership/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/membership/</guid>
      <description>Come Join Us If you are blind or visually impaired, all you need to become a member of the USBCAUSBCA is the desire and the readiness to enjoy some great games of chess. Membership is absolutely free.&#xA;As a member of the USBCA, you get:&#xA;The ability to play in correspondence and realtime chess tournaments and friendly games with other members Your own correspondence and realtime ratings Your name and rating on the USBCA correspondence and realtime ratings lists Access to The USBCAUSBCA Braill Library of chess material.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rules for Tournament Play With And Between Blind Players</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/rules2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/rules2/</guid>
      <description>Rules Adapted For Blind And Visually-impaired People SUPPLEMENT TO THE FIDE LAWS OF CHESS Competitive games between visually impaired and sighted players and between visually impaired players&#xA;Tournament Directors shall have the power to adapt the following rules according to local circumstances:&#xA;In competitive Chess between sighted and visually impaired players (legally blind) either player may demand the use of two boards, the sighted player using a normal board, the visually impaired player using one specially constructed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Rules Of Chess</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/rules/</guid>
      <description>Rules of the Game of Chess The following sections contain some basic chess rules quoted from the official rules of chess as laid down by the International Chess Federation (F.I.D.E.).&#xA;For some supplemental rules for tournament play with and between blind players, go to Supplemental Rules for playing with and between blind players&#xA;ARTICLE 1: INTRODUCTION The game of chess is played between two opponents by moving pieces on a square board called a &amp;quot;chessboard&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>USBCA 2024 Ladder TournamentStandings</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/ladder-standings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/ladder-standings/</guid>
      <description>This is where you can find the United States Blind Chess Association correspondence Ladder tournament standings.&#xA;Tournament Director Contact Information&#xD;Please write this information down somewhere other than on your computer in case you do&#xD;not have access to your computer when you need it. It is your responsibility to keep this contact&#xD;information where you can access it.&#xD;Tournament director: Mario Montalvo&#xD;Tournament director email: superfoxpro@gmail.com&#xD;Tournament Director cell phone (text or call): 832-997-2511&#xD;Official 2024 Ladder Standings 2023 Ladder Tornament champion, Jim Thoune</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
