<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Challenger: Magazine of the United States Blind Chess Association on The United States Blind Chess Association</title>
    <link>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Challenger: Magazine of the United States Blind Chess Association on The United States Blind Chess Association</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Challenger, First Quarter, 2024</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2024-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2024-03/</guid>
      <description>The Challenger Magazine of the United States Blind Chess Association December 2023&#xA;The mission of the USBCA is to promote the game of chess among the blind community. Website: http://usblindchess.org/&#xA;Disclaimer The views expressed in the Challenger do not necessarily reflect the policies or views of the USBCA or those of the editor.&#xA;President&amp;rsquo;s Message Well, another term has come and gone, and a new one is upon us. My thanks to those of you who exercised your right as USBCA members and cast your ballot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Challenger, Second Quarter, 2024</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2024-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2024-06/</guid>
      <description>The Challenger Magazine of the United States Blind Chess Association&#xA;June 2024&#xA;The mission of the USBCA is to promote the game of chess among the blind community.&#xA;Website: https://usblindchess.org&#xA;Note: The views expressed in the Challenger do not necessarily reflect the policies or views of the USBCA or those of the editor.&#xA;Editor’s Note By Rita Crawford&#xA;The mission of the USBCA is to promote chess among the blind community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Challenger, Fourth Quarter, 2023</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2023-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2023-12/</guid>
      <description>The Challenger Disclaimer Editor&amp;rsquo;s Note Upcoming Events Chess Queens Hands On Chess Chat Important Notice Getting to Know President&amp;rsquo;s Note Change Is Afoot! Greece and Guatemala Player&amp;rsquo;s Spotlight Annotated game by Paul Benson Puzzles Easy Position Solution Harder Position Solution Difficult Position Solution The Challenger Magazine of the United States Blind Chess Association December 2023&#xA;The mission of the USBCA is to promote the game of chess among the blind community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Challenger, Third Quarter, 2023</title>
      <link>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2023-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://.usblindchess.org/challenger/2023-09/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Table of Contents Disclaimer Important Notices Upcoming Events Notice Board Results of US Blind Open held in Elmhurst, IL July 21 to 23, 2023 Results of the Stephen Hilton Memorial chess tournament In Memoriam, Norm Doerner Editor&amp;rsquo;s Note President&amp;rsquo;s Message: The USBCA! Who Am Us, anyway! (The Firesign Theater) Player Spotlight, U.S. Blind Open Champion Alex Barrasso Champing At The Bit Part 2 Down To The Last Seconds Puzzles Mate in 2 and 3 Mate in two.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
